Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to create Arranged Enemy, which will shoot projectiles
at the player character from a safe location.
So to get started, I'm going to create a new folder and call it mushroom.
Then head inside this folder and briefly close on your engine attached in the lecture for this course,
I'm going to make sure to include this file called Mushroom so that all the images inside of it and
just drag this into this folder.
Once you've done that, select all the images right click and go expressions and apply paper to texture
settings.
I then want you to create a folder for each of the animations.
Once you've done that, move each image to its respected folder.
First, let's go over how to set up the range attack.
If we head inside this folder, I'm going to set the range attack image and go expressions extract right
and go to grid.
Then under cell width per value of 150 and extract.
Then I'm going to set all the sprites right click and go create a flipbook and we can just pull this
mushroom ranged attack.
Then if you just select the product outright, right click and go Spy actions and extract sprites.
Go to auto and select grid.
Then on to sell with if you put 50 and just go extract.
And for this project, I'll write the first four images.
Right click and go create a flipbook and call this mushroom projectile.
So this is the flipbook.
We're going to show it of our mushroom when it's shooting its projectile.
Then for the last four frames of the mushroom projectile, select them and just go right click, create
flipbook and call this mushroom projectile explode.
So when our mushroom projectile hit something, we're going to make it play this explosion flipbook.
Okay, So now I'm going to create the other animations for my mushroom.
It's going to be exactly the same as how we created the animations for the Scantron.
So if you want to skip ahead, I understand, although I'm still going to do it, I'll put a timestamp
somewhere on the screen if you want to skip ahead.
So first of all, I'm going to start with the take here animation.
I'll go into this folder and just right click and go explore actions and extract sprites.
Under Sprite trick mode, I'm going go grid and change the cell width to be 150 and we can extract the
sprites.
I'll set all of them right click and go create a flipbook and I'll call this mushroom.
Hit.
Then if I just double click, I remember last time it was very quick.
So under frames per second I would make the six just so it's a bit slower when we hit our mushroom.
Next, if we go to the idle folder, right click spy actions and extract rights under threat extract
mode.
I'm going to go ahead and change this to 150.
Go extract and offset for the sprites.
Right click and create a flipbook and I'll call this mushroom idol.
Then if we head over to death, I'm going to right click Spray Actions.
Extract Sprite's under sprite extract mode.
I'll go grid and and set width.
I'll change this to be 150.
Go extract.
And I'm going to let all the sprites create flipbook.
I'll call this mushroom.
Yes.
Then I'm going to select the last bright right click and call this mushroom dead body.
Next, I'm going to create a new photo and just call it flip books.
So I right click and go new folder.
And I call this flip books.
Then if we just let all the animation folders and just move them into this folder just to keep everything
organized.
Then I'm going to create a new folder and call this animations.
And if we hadn't sat here next, if we just right click and look for Peoples CD and select animation
source, just cool this mushroom animation source.
Then if we double click and head inside here.
Hanukkah Avenue and select new animation sequence.
And I will call the first one Mushroom Idol.
And here on the animation data.
I'm going to select my mushroom idol.
Then if we go add new new animation sequence and I'm cool, the second one, Mushroom.
Take damage.
And other animation data will suck the mushroom hit.
Then I'm going to add new.
And I'm going to add the mushroom range to attack.
And I'm going to set the mushroom ranged attack animation.
Then I go add new new animation sequence and I call this mushroom die.
And I'm going to tell you mushroom death.
Then I'm going to add new, new animation sequence and I'll call this mushroom dead body.
And I also like the mushroom dead body.
Then we can just save this and close this.
Next.
I want us to just right click and create a new folder and call this blueprint.
And if we hadn't sat here and Right Click and Go Blueprint class and all classes, look for Paper Z.
Select a.
And just cool this mushroom.
Underscore BP.
And if we hadn't sat here.
Under Sprite.
I'm just going to set my mushroom idle.
And I'm going to make my mushroom character fit inside this capsule.
So I'll make it like.
By.
And that is looking good.
Finally, if we just close this and go back to our animation folder, just right click and go Paper
Z and select Paper Z animation blueprint.
This time we want to set the mushroom animation source and I'm going to call this mushroom and beep.
If we hadn't sat here and I went on end, we just want to right click and forget owning actor.
And a struggle paying the full costs to mushroom.
BP hook up event into here and right click on it and promote it to a variable so you can reference it
later.
We can go compile.
And if we go over to our graph, I'm just going to right click create a new state machine.
Pick us up here.
Head inside here and out.
I'm going to look for animation set, and I'll call this idol.
Then if we head inside here, I'm going to play the mushroom.
I do.
I'll compile and save everything.
And then if I go back to my machine.
BP And under animation component, let's just make sure if using the mushroom animation blueprint so
it's like mushroom and beep.
So now we set up the base importing of our mushroom character.
In the next lecture, we'll code it so our mushroom can attack our player from a safe distance.